# ALEXANDRA LARRABEE

**Location:** Minneapolis, MN 55435 • **Phone:** 763-213-2262 • **Email:** alexlarrabee10@gmail.com **LinkedIn:** linkedin.com/in/alexandra-larrabee • **GitHub:** github.com/alarrabee

#### **SUMMARY**

Motivated full-stack web developer with extensive experience in analytical chemistry and laboratory management and a graduate from the University of Minnesota's Coding Bootcamp. Committed to continuous learning, adaptability, collaboration, and delivering successful and timely results.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Languages & Frameworks: JavaScript, Node.js, Express, React, HTML, CSS, SQL, NoSQL
- Tools & Platforms: Git/GitHub, Render, Insomnia, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, Jest
- Design: Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Materialize, Tailwind
- Other: API Development, User Authentication, MS Excel

#### **PROJECTS**

Paws and Claws (06/2024)

Animal adoption application

- GitHub: Paws and Claws
- Technologies: Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Handlebars, Bcrypt, Materialize
- **Contributions:** Frontend development and design, enhancing user experience through responsive design and efficient routing.

# **Chirp Finder** (04/2024)

Searchable collection of bird recordings and facts

- GitHub: Chirp Finder
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON/API
- Contributions: Backend development, implemented robust API calls, and ensured seamless data integration.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## SurModics Inc - Eden Prairie, MN

Senior Scientist (06/2023 - Present)

Scientist (01/2019 - 06/2023)

Associate Scientist (05/2015 - 12/2018)

# Subject matter expert for SEC-MALS and planning and conducting laboratory experiments for drug delivery projects.

- Conduct and report comprehensive data analyses for R&D projects, maintaining on-time delivery rate of results.
- Train and mentor junior scientists and interns, improving team performance.
- Maintained and troubleshooted lab instrumentation, reducing downtime.

### Aveda, Estee Lauder Companies - Blaine, MN

Laboratory Technician (06/2014 - 05/2015)

Responsible for the testing of raw materials and manufactured goods to assure compliance with written specifications.

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Women Coders Network (04/2024)

• Assisted in setting up and developing the network's website, fostering a supportive community for women in tech.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Minnesota/Trilogy Coding Bootcamp - St Paul, MN

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate (Expected 08/2024)

Winona State University - Winona, MN

Bachelor of Science in Chemistry (08/2010 - 05/2014)